cultivate.com 2013-09-05

# Cultivate Privacy Policy | Cultivate

Revised:  December 26, 2012

Your privacy is very important to us.  We have prepared this Privacy Policy to explain how we collect, use protect, and disclose information and data when you use the Cultivate website (" ** _Site_** ") or Cultivate services (" ** _Services_** ").  The Site and Services are made available and operated by Williams-Sonoma, Inc. (" ** _Williams-Sonoma_** " " ** _we_** " " ** _us_** ").  By using the Site or Services, you consent to this Privacy Policy. 

**Information We Collect**

**_Collecting Information about You_**

We may collect information about you, such as your name, username, address, zip code, email, phone number and other information that you choose to provide us (" ** _Contact Information_** ").  You may be asked to provide us with Contact Information when you register with the Site or use certain Services, and at other times.  If you access the Site or Services through Facebook Connect, you understand that some content and/or information in your Facebook account (“ ** _Third Party Account Information_** ”) may be transmitted into your account with us if you authorize such transmissions, and that Third Party Account Information transmitted to our Site or Services is covered by this Privacy Policy.  The decision to provide any or all of the information we request is optional.  However, if you choose not to provide the requested information, you may not be able to use some or all of the features of the Site or Services.

**_Usage Data and Site Activity_**

We automatically collect information regarding the actions you take on the Site, such as the type of Web browser you use, your operating system, your Internet Service Provider, your IP address, the pages you view, and the time and duration of your visits to the Site, and other similar information (" ** _Usage Data_** ").  This anonymous Usage Data may be associated with your username, but we do not disclose the associated information to third parties except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy.  We use Usage Data to help us understand how people use the Site and Services, and to enhance the services we offer. 

**_Cookies and Web Beacons_**

We use cookies (a small text file placed on your computer to identify your computer and browser).  We also use Web beacons (an electronic file placed on a website that monitors usage).  We use cookies and Web beacons to improve the experience of the Site and Services, such as pre-populating your username for easier login.  We do not use cookies or Web beacons to collect Contact Information.  Most Web browsers are initially set up to accept cookies.  You can reset your Web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent.  However, certain features of the Site or Services may not work if you delete or disable cookies.  Some of our Service Providers may use their own cookies and Web beacons in connection with the services they perform on our behalf.

**Using Information About You**

We use your Contact Information and Usage Data for internal purposes, such as:

· providing the Site and Services to you;

· analyzing preferences, trends, and statistics;

· informing you of products, services, promotions, and offers that may be of interest to you; and

· providing you with other information from and about Cultivate and the “Williams-Sonoma, Inc. Brands," which include Williams-Sonoma, Pottery Barn, pottery barn kids, PBteen, west elm, Rejuvenation and Mark and Graham. 

From time to time we establish business relationships with other persons or entities whom we believe trustworthy and whom we have asked to confirm that their privacy policies are consistent with ours.  These are known as our Select Partners.  In such cases we may rent, sell, exchange, share and/or cross-reference information, including Contact Information, about you that will enable such persons or entities to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you.

To serve you better, we may combine information you give us online on the Site as well as in stores or through catalogs of the Williams-Sonoma, Inc. Brands.  We may also combine that information with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our Select Partners and others.  We use that combined information to enhance and personalize the shopping experience of you and others with us, to communicate with you about our products and events that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes.

We may contract with companies or persons to provide certain services including data management, promotional services, etc.  We call them our Service Providers.  We provide our Service Providers with the information needed for them to perform these services.  We also ask our Service Providers to confirm that their privacy practices are consistent with ours.

We may allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit the Site.  These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to the Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of interest to you.  These companies typically use a cookie or third-party Web beacon to collect this information.  To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [_http://www.networkadvertising.org/_](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

We may share contact information and other data with businesses controlling, controlled by, or under common control with any Williams-Sonoma, Inc. Brands.

In certain instances we may disclose your Contact Information and Usage Data when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against persons or entities who may be causing injury to you, the Site, Williams-Sonoma, or to others, and when we believe the law or legal process requires it.  We may also share Contact Information and Usage Data with businesses controlling, controlled by, or under common control with Williams-Sonoma. 

**Opting Out Of Marketing And Transfers; Managing Information About You**

We want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us.  If you prefer not to receive marketing communications from us or from our Select Partners, or if you would like to opt out of our exchange of your information with other marketers, please let us know.  You can call us at1.800.541.1262or send us an [email](http://www.williams-sonomainc.com/contact-us/).  Please be sure to include your full name, email address, and specifically what information you do not want to receive.  If you would like to update or correct your Contact Information with us please contact us the same way.

You may also click the designated link at the bottom of all email advertisements to be removed from future email updates.

Please note that any requests to remove or update your contact information may take up to ten days for your email request.

**Be Careful When You Share Information with Others**

Please be aware that whenever you share information on a publicly available profile page or any other public forum on the Site, that information may be accessed by others.  In addition, please remember that when you share information in any other communications with third parties that information may be passed along or made public by others.  This means that anyone with access to such information can potentially use it for any purpose, including sending unsolicited communications.

**Security**

We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the confidentiality and security of information transmitted to us.  However, no data transmission over the Internet or other network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  As a result, while we strive to protect information transmitted on or through the Site or Services, we cannot and do not guarantee the security of any information you transmit on or through the Site or Services, and you do so at your own risk.

**Links To Other Websites and Services**

Our Site and Services may contain links to other websites or online services, or allow others to send you such links.  A link to a third party's website or service does not mean that we endorse it or that we are affiliated with it.  We do not exercise control over third-party websites or services.  You access such third-party websites or services at your own risk.  You should always read the privacy policy of a third-party website or service before providing any information on or through it.

**Children's Privacy**

The Site and Services are intended for users who are 18 years old or older.  We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13.  If we become aware that we have inadvertently received information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete such information from our records.

**Processing in the United States   **

Please be aware that your Contact Information and communications may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province, or country.  If you are located outside of the United States, please be advised that we process and store all information in the United States.  The laws in the United States may not be as protective of your privacy as those in your location.  By using our Site or Services, you agree that the collection, use, transfer, and disclosure of your Contact Information and communications will be governed by the applicable laws in the United States.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

From time to time, we may change this Privacy Policy.  If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will inform you by posting the revised Privacy Policy on the Site.  Those changes will go into effect on the Revision Date shown in the revised Privacy Policy.  Your continued use of our Site or Services constitutes your consent to the revised Privacy Policy.
